MICHAEL HUTCHINGS

@ mdhutchings94@gmail.com

+447504605355

• Cambridge, UK

midanosi.netlify.app

nidanosi 🕜

w midanosi

Frontend TS/JS Developer

with **5 years** experience in building robust and slick user interfaces. I specialise in frontend development, and also work in neighbouring disciplines; **backend development**, **UI/UX design**, and **automated testing**.

I'm looking to join a collaborative team to build functional and engaging applications!

EXPERIENCE

Evonetix

Senior Engineer

Apr 2022 - Mar 2023

• Cambridge, UK

- Developed in-house "recipe" generation website used in the DNA synthesis process
- Created feature mockups and wireframes, and iterated on designs with scientists and software engineers
- Mentored junior team members in programming and team-working skills
- Fostered a team habit of pragmatic documentation
- Evaluated current browser automation tools and created a Playwright test suite

Cambridge Consultants

Senior Engineer

📩 Jan 2021 - Apr 2022

• Cambridge, UK

- Led frontend development on three client projects of length 3-6 months
- Proposed and developed new functionality to meet client needs
- Demonstrated versatility by taking on backend development responsibilities for one client project
- Greater involvement in the interview process; screening CVs, revamping outdated interview question content, conducting office tours for candidates, and co-running interviews

Engineer

🗖 Jan 2019 - Jan 2021

• Cambridge, UK

- Delivered customised and complex UI features across several client and internal projects
- Presented UI work to clients and project stakeholders on a regular basis
- Collaborated across different disciplines (Backend, Design, AI), contributed to technical discussions outside of my typical domain
- Evaluated emerging tools such as Cypress, Svelte, XState, TypeScript, Yarn, Vite, pnpm
- Developed and maintained automated test suites for multiple projects
- Mentored and supported a placement student within our team

Luminance

Web Developer

📩 Jan 2018 - Dec 2018

• Cambridge, UK

- Coded many new features of the web application, committed many bug fixes
- Successfully met numerous short and intense deadlines
- Organised and prioritised tickets onto a kanban board for each release

CGI

Manual Software Tester

Aug 2014 - Aug 2015

• Leatherhead, UK

- Worked on the Galileo Satellite Navigation System project
- Became a thorough and exact manual software tester. At end of year, performed a full test suite
 in front of clients over a two week period
- Improved technical communication skills, driven by necessarily precise bug reports

EDUCATION

University of Bath

Sept 2012 - June 2016

BSc (Hons)

Mathematics

(with Sandwich Placement)

• Classification: 1st

SKILLS

JavaScript TypeScript

HTML/CSS Python

React Svelte SvelteKit

Next.js

open to other frameworks

git GitLab CI/CD Firebase

AWS Azure

Zustand XState

Redux + Toolkit Jotai

react-query

React Three Fiber GSAP

Threlte Three.js

react-spring

Framer Balsamiq Figma

Playwright Vitest Jest

Testing Library Cypress

MacOS Linux Windows

INTERESTS

🏅 Skiing

🕏 Running

Synthwave

Electronic